不不
No, no. No.
-这都是什么  -天呐
- What is all that? - Oh, my lord.
这些袋子里
Somewhere in one of these bags
装着一件给珍妮和莱恩的完美婴儿送礼会礼物
is the perfect baby shower gift for Jen and Ryan.
我只需要你们帮我选一个
I just need your help picking which one.
准备好了吗
Ready?
-不行  -那是一件婴儿防弹衣吗
- No. - Is that a bulletproof baby ve--
-这简直太过分了  -天呐
- It's completely inappropriate. - Oh, my...
-错得离谱  -不是吧  好吧
- So wrong. - Really? Okay.
那你们肯定不喜欢
Well, then, you're gonna hate the onesies
写着"我旁边是笨蛋警官"的连体衣
that say "I'm with officer stupid."
理查德  真是的
Richard, I... honestly.
你为什么不能买一件普通传统的
Why can't you just buy a simple tradition--
为什么这事对你来说那么难
Why is that so difficult for you?
不难啊  接下来这件绝对完美
It's not. This next one is perfect.
-相信我  -好吧
- Trust me. - Okay.
是婴儿款的电光剑吗
Is it a baby-sized lightsaber?
不是
No.
拜托告诉我那个不是唱里昂纳德·科恩
Please tell me that's not the creepy robot nanny
摇篮曲的恐怖机器人保姆
that sings Leonard Cohen lullabies.
里昂纳德·科恩摇篮曲怎么了
What's wrong with Leonard Cohen lullabies?
感觉更像《沉默的羔羊》这样的恐怖片
It's more like "Silence of the Lambs"
而不是《玛丽有只小羊羔》那样的儿歌
Than "Mary Had a Little Lamb."
别担心  亲爱的
Oh, don't worry, sweetheart.
幸好
Fortunately,
阿丽克西斯已经为婴儿送礼会买了完美的礼物
Alexis has purchased the perfect baby shower gift.
你只需要在礼物卡上签字
All you have to do is sign the card.
你们知道找到可机洗
Do you have any idea how hard it is
防弹衣是多难吗
to find machine-washable kevlar?
我去买东西之前你们怎么不说
Why didn't you tell me this before I went shopping?
因为那样我们就折磨不到你了
Because we would have so missed torturing you.
你是我们最喜欢的真人秀
You are our favorite reality show.
很高兴我能为你们带来欢乐
I'm so happy I could entertain you.
多谢了  阿丽克西斯
Thank you, Alexis.
我稍后就送去分局
I will drop this off at the precinct a little later.
很遗憾你去不了送礼会
Too bad you can't go to the shower.
贝克特在分手中分到了婴儿送礼会
Oh, well, Beckett got, uh, baby showers in the break-up, so...
真逗  最近你...
That's funny, 'cause you... recently you just, uh,
似乎不那么受那件事困扰了
Don't seem to be so tortured by all that.
贝克特要我再给她点时间的嘛
Oh, well, you know, Beckett asked for some time,
所以我要成全她
So I'm just giving it to her.
-每天都给  -好吧
- Every day. - Well...
-有时候还两次  -什么
- Sometimes twice. - What?
这太棒了  多谢
See, this is nice. Thank you so much.
-嗯  不客气  -再见
- Yeah. No problem. - Bye.
早啊
Morning.
被害人是俄国人
So, our vic is a Russian national.
-名叫  -格里戈里·米什金
- Name of, uh... - Grigory Mishkin.
我跟局长通过电话
I spoke to the police commissioner.
他是一位领事馆官员的儿子
He's the son of a consulate officer,
所以这事可能变成政治事件
which means this might get political.
太好
Great.
蕾妮  什么情况
Lanie, so what do we got?
被割喉
Throat was slashed.
根据尸温死亡时间是凌晨2点到4点间
Liver temp puts the time of death between 2:00 and 4:00 a.m.
是否知道被害人
Any idea what our victim was doing
为什么会大晚上来废弃大楼
in an abandoned building in the middle of the night?
不知道  他的兜被翻过
No. His pockets were turned out,
但他的钱包和手机就在附近
but his wallet and cellphone were found nearby.
凶手搜了他的身
So the killer searched him,
但无从得知是否有东西被拿走
but there's no way to know if anything was taken.
蕾妮  你怎么看这个
Lanie, what do you make of these?
看来是他之前衬衫里的东西
Looks like ink that was transferred
印上去的墨迹
from whatever was in his shirt.
看看实验室是否能重组字迹
See if the lab can reconstruct the characters.
他可能是因为本来在里面的东西被杀
He might have been killed because of whatever was inside.
-好  -谢谢
- Yeah. - Thanks.
好啊
Howdy.
"好啊"
"Howdy"?
嗯  "诶"有点腻味了
Yeah, um, "Yo" is getting played out,
所以我想换个花样
So I thought I'd try something new.
你还是继续换吧  "好啊"太...
You might want to keep trying, 'cause "Howdy" is just...
不对劲了
Wrong.
我喜欢嘛
Well, I like it.
对了  街区下方有个
Oh, by the way, there's a homeless guy
流浪汉住在那里
that was camped out down the block.
他凌晨2:30听到一辆车呼啸而过
He heard a car roar to life, burned rubber around 2:30 a.m.,
所以我会去调街头监控看看
So I'm pulling the street cam footage.
好  有消息通知我
All right, keep me posted.
我去俄国跟他的亲属谈谈
I'm gonna head off to Russia and talk to the next of kin.
-俄国  -什么
- Russia? - What?
从法律上讲
Uh, legally,
领事馆属于外国领土  所以
a consulate is considered foreign territory, so...
好吧  回见
All right, see you later.
我是帕维尔·奥伯林总领事
I'm Consul General Pavel Oborin.
纽约警局  凯特·贝克特警监
Captain Kate Beckett, NYPD.
见到你很荣幸奥伯林先生
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Oborin.
你好  警监
Yes, captain.
我这就带你去见格里戈里的父亲  谢尔盖
I will take you to Grigory's father, Sergei.
他希望能尽快解决此案  伸张正义
He hopes for a quick resolution and to see justice served.
我们也是  是否会是
As do we. Now, is it possible that
格里戈里父亲在领事馆的工作让他涉险
Grigory's father's consulate work put his son at risk?
米什金先生是为商品做经济预期的
Oh, Mr. Mishkin writes economic forecasts for commodities.
实在不值得为之杀人
It's hardly a thing worth killing for.
你认识格里戈里吗
And did you know Grigory?
是的
Oh, yes.
我看着他长大的
I watched him grow up.
这事我们很上心
You see, for us this is very personal.
我理解
I understand.
那你一定不会反对
Then you will be amenable to my request
我派一位俄国外交安全人员
to have a Russian diplomatic security officer
跟随这件案子
assigned to the case.
奥伯林先生  多谢你的心意
Uh, Mr. Oborin, I appreciate the offer,
但我的警探是城里最棒的
but my detectives are the best in the city.
这我不怀疑
Well, I do not doubt that.
但我还是要坚持
But still I must insist.
合作精神
A spirit of cooperation
对大家都有好处
is in everyone's best interest.
你能告诉我格里戈里到底发生了什么吗
Please, can you tell me what happened with Grigory?
我们现在还不完全确定
Uh, we're not exactly sure just yet.
你是否知道他为什么会去一栋废弃大楼
Do you have any idea what he was doing in an abandoned building?
我也希望我知道
I wish I did.
格里戈里自从他母亲
Grigory hasn't been himself
安雅因车祸去世后就变了个人
since we lost his mother, Anya, in a car accident.
上月  他越来越消沉
The last month has been a downward spiral of...
酗酒  吸毒
of drinking, drugs.
那么他可能是去见一个毒贩
So he could have been meeting with a dealer.
我不知道
I wouldn't know.
但他最近换的那批新朋友可能知道
But the new crowd he was spending time with would.
是一批什么样的新朋友
And what crowd is this?
-外二代  -什么
- Diplobrats. - What...
外交官被宠坏的孩子
Spoiled children of foreign officers
凭外交豁免权就藐视法律
who flaunt the law with diplomatic immunity.
他们随心所欲  也没人能阻拦他们
They do what they like, and nobody can stop them.
格里戈里在他们的世界里迷失了
Grigory got lost in their world.
这是臭名昭著的纽约市外二代
Meet the notorious diplobrats of New York city.
我们可以逮捕他们  但有豁免权他们不会被追责
We arrest them, but immunity means no prosecution.
这就像抓与放的游戏
So it's like catch and release
但没有凉啤酒喝
but without the cooler full of beer.
是啊  我还在翻查他们的文件
Yeah, I'm searching through all their files,
看看是否跟被害人有联系
see if there's a connection back to our vic.
目前尚无发现
But so far, nothing.
你听说了吗  俄国人要派个自己人过来
Hey, did you hear the Russians are sending one of their own
-跟我们一起查案  -开玩笑吧
- to ride along with us? - Are you kidding me?
瓦西里·茨洛夫
Vasily Zhirov.
他是俄国外交安全人员
He's part of the Russian diplomatic security service.
-红色警探要来吗  -卡塞尔
- "Red heat" is coming here? - Oh! Castle.
还带来了礼物
Bearing gifts, I see.
这是给小凯文的启动包
This is your starter kit for little Kevin.
除了那瓶25年麦卡伦和耳塞
Except for the Macallan 25 and the earplugs.
那是给你的
Those are for you.
你真是个周到的好男人
You're a dear and thoughtful man.
我知道  俄国人啊
I know. So, a Russian?
是啊  伊凡·德拉格[电影反派]要来了
Yeah, Ivan Drago's in the house.
听说他们都像机器人一样  公事公办
I hear those guys are like automatons. Strictly business.
鲍里斯要来了  那娜塔莎也快来了[动画人物]
Well, if Boris is coming, could Natasha be far behind?
这下大驼鹿
This could be trouble
和小松鼠要惨了[梗同上]
for the big moose and little squirrel.
-这...他就在我身后吧  -对
- It's so... he's right behind me, isn't he? - Yeah.
我认识你
I know you.
你是理查德·卡塞尔吧
You're Richard Castle, no?
是啊
Yes.
太荣幸了
It's such an honor!
我更荣幸
The honor is mine, I assure you.
我爱死你的书了
I love your books.
很多去莫斯科的漫漫旅行
Many a flight to Moscow,
都是德里克·斯道姆陪我度过
I've been kept company by Derrick Storm.
还有妮基·希特
And Nikki Heat.
也是贝克特警监
Also known as Captain Beckett.
能见到他的缪斯  灵感来源也很荣幸
It's also an honor to meet the muse, the inspiration.
欢迎你来12分局  茨洛夫先生
Yeah, uh, welcome to the 12th, Mr. Zhirov.
多么著名的破案二人组
Such a famous crime-solving duo.
能看你们工作是我莫大的荣幸
It will be a privilege to watch you work.
很遗憾  我们现在不再合作了
Uh, well, sadly, we don't work together any longer.
那怎么可能
But it cannot be.
贝克特离开卡塞尔就像鲍里斯离开娜塔莎
Beckett without Castle is like, uh, Boris without Natasha.
就像没有了哈奇的斯塔基[电影搭档]
It's like Starsky without the Hutch.
就是"哈奇"
It's just Hutch.
不带冠词
Not "the Hutch."
你刚刚说的是...
You said "the Hutch."
街头监控没能拍到逃逸车
Uh, street cams weren't able to get our getaway car,
但枪击分辨系统被引擎声启动了
but ShotSpotter was tripped by the engine noise.
那是什么
What is, uh, spot shotter?
枪击分辨系统
ShotSpotter.
用于探测枪击的音频监控系统
Audio surveillance system designed to detect gunshots.
超过120分贝的声音也会启动系统
And noises over 120 decibels can also activate the system,
所以我们录到了音
So we got a recording.
知道吗  我去找
You know what? I'll just have to get,
专家帮我分析是什么车型吧
uh, experts to tell me what kind of make and model.
不必  那是一辆兰博基尼飓风
No need. That is a Lamborghini Huracán.
V10款出了名的
Yeah, the v-10s are notorious
声音清脆响亮
for crackling and popping like a breakfast cereal.
尤尔根·卡斯
Jurgen Kass.
芬兰大使之子
The son of the Finnish ambassador
就开这辆车
has that very same car.
他还有吸毒和袭人的过往指控
He also has a history of drug and assault charges,
当然  因为他有外交豁免权
though, of course, all of those charges were dropped
这些指控都被撤销
due to his diplomatic immunity.
凶杀可不能豁免  我们去找他
Well, murder doesn't get a pass, so pick him up.
卡塞尔先生  你这就让案子获得了重大突破
Mr. Castle, you already have broken open the case.
嗯  我也很想留下
Yeah. You know, I'd be glad to stick around...
但我还有其他事要做
but I actually have some business to attend to, so...
又来了
There we go.
我该走了
I should go.
那么...嗯
So... Oh. Yes.
-好啊  警察  -尤尔根
- What's up, five-oh? - Ah, Jurgen.
我看你还不明白你是惹了什么麻烦
I don't think you understand the trouble you're in.
拜托  我没惹麻烦
Oh, please. I ain't in trouble.
我就是麻烦
I am trouble.
是啊  你是个疤面煞星
Oh, yeah. You're a regular scarface.
给我坐下
Sit down. Now.
你觉得你能吓住我吗  警察
You think you scare me, five-oh?
拜托  就算我现在掏鸟出来
Please. I could put my little man on this table,
你也做不了什么
and there's not one thing you could do.
如果你让我看见你的鸟
If I see your little man,
那我们就有麻烦了
we're gonna have a little problem.
-这家伙  -坐下
- This guy. - Sit down.
你担心我是来给你添麻烦的
You are worried I'm here to make troubles for you.
不是  不是这样
No. No, of course not.
警监
Captain,
你真想用谎言开始我们的友谊吗
do you really want to start off this friendship with a lie?
好吧
Okay, fine.
事实是  一个年轻人被杀
The truth... a young man was murdered,
我不希望政治妨碍我
and I don't want politics to get in the way
抓到凶手
of catching the bastard who did it.
我佩服你的激情
I admire your passion.
很有俄国味儿
Very Russian.
放心  我并不想插手你的案子
Rest assured, I do not wish to interfere in your case.
我是最不像政客的人了
I'm as far from the political animal as one can get.
老实说  我很激动能跟伟大的凯瑟琳学习
Frankly, I am excid to learn from Katherine the Great.
我可以跟你说个秘密吗
May I share a secret?
当然
Uh, yes.
我从未来过纽约
I've never been to New York.
我本希望有空能
And I was hoping there will be some downtime
去观光一番
for me to see the sights.
当然
Uh, yes. Of course.
事实上  我可以等到了重要时刻再叫你来
In fact, I can bring you in for the important moments.
其他时候  你可以尽情去城里转
And otherwise, the city is yours to explore.
你去仓库区开车兜了风
You went for a little ride in the Warehouse District.
我们知道你昨晚去了那栋废弃公寓楼
We know you were at that abandoned building last night.
你去那儿见了格里戈里  好卖他毒品
You met Grigory there to sell him drugs.
他出尔反尔  你便杀了他
And then when he stiffed you, you killed him.
好吧
All right.
我承认
I confess.
I confess that, uh,
我有钱  小婊砸
I am rich, bitches.
说"茄子"
Say "cheese."
你怎么回事  你干什么呢
The hell's wrong with you? What are you doing?
你是一宗谋杀案调查的首要嫌疑人
You're the prime suspect in a murder investigation.
你们知道我有外交豁免权
You know I have diplomatic immunity.
要起诉我  你国国务院
To charge me, your State Department
得向我国政府征询允许  而现在不是这样
has to ask my government's permission, which they have not.
但这经历很愉快
But, um, this has been awesome.
再见了
Peace out.
嫌疑人走了
The suspect is leaving.
是啊  案子一般不像
Yeah, cases don't always get solved
卡塞尔书里那样解决的那么快
as quickly as they do in Castle's books.
那你们接下来怎么办
What will you do next?
继续查  看能不能查到关于尤尔根的铁证
Just keep digging till we find some hard evidence on Jurgen.
所以你现在正好可以
Means that now might be a good time
去做我们刚刚说的那件事
to go do that thing that we talked about.
谢谢
Spasibo.
-他去哪  -观光
- Where's he going? - Sightseeing.
看来他不会给我们找麻烦了
Looks like he won't be a problem after all.
理查德·卡塞尔侦探社
Richard Castle Investigations.
我是瓦西里
This is Vasily.
我有重大消息要跟你商量
I have most important news to discuss.
那个  如果是关于案子
Uh, listen, if it's about the case...
不是的  是这样  我也是个作家
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. You see, I'm a writer, too.
当然了
Of course you are.
我有个关于《妮基·希特》小说的点子
I have an idea for a Nikki Heat novel.
-当然了  -我们一起喝咖啡吧
- Of course you do. - Let's meet for coffee.
我...看看我的日程
Let me... let me... I'm gonna check my schedule.
瓦西里·茨洛夫想约我喝咖啡
Vasily Zhirov wants me to meet him for coffee.
-我怎么办  -哄他开心
- What should I do? - Keep him happy.
他跟你待得越久
The more time he spends with you,
就越不会来打扰我
the less he's gonna be hanging over my shoulder.
如果我能哄住他呢
And if I keep him happy?
那我就让你开心
Then I will keep you happy.
没问题  瓦西里
Done. Vasily!
书名就叫《火与冰》
The title of the book will be "Heat and Ice."
而冰是新出场的俄国超级间谍的代号
Ice is the code name for the new Russian super spy
他是妮基·希特的新死敌
who is Nikki Heat's new nemesis.
来自东方的敌人  新冷战
Enemy from the east. A new cold war.
冷战  没错
Cold war! Yes!
但希特和冰虽然是对手
But though heat and ice are rivals,
但他们的性吸引力却如核能之火
their sexual attraction is like nuclear fire!
瓦西里
Vasily.
我得说  你跟我想的大不一样
I, uh, have to admit you are not at all what I expected.
你以为我会是个"红色警探"
You thought I'd be like... "Red Heat."
是啊
Yeah.
那是老俄国了
That is old Russia.
我是新俄国
I am new Russia.
那不是嫌疑人吗
Isn't that our suspect?
真巧啊
What a coincidence.
你的警探朋友审问他没审出什么来
Your detective friends didn't have much luck questioning him.
或许我们能做得更好
I wonder if we can do better.
或许我们还是别管了
Oh, maybe we should leave it alone.
或许我们不该插手
Maybe we shouldn't interfere, uh...
你好
Hello.
你们是谁
Who are you?
看看书吧  小伙子
Hey, pick up book, young man.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
This here is Richard Castle,
我们当代最棒的悬疑小说作家之一
one of the great mystery writers of our time.
他有几个问题要问你
And he has a few questions for you
事关格里戈里·米什金被杀一案
about the murder of Grigory Mishkin.
滚蛋吧  伊凡
Oh, get lost, Ivan.
警察都不敢动我  你们又能做什么
If the cops can't touch me, what are you guys going to do?
外交豁免权啊
Diplomatic immunity.
就像一件柔软的皮毛大衣  让你温暖舒服
It is like a soft fur coat that keeps you warm and cozy.
至少在美国
In America.
但是  朋友  俄国正义的规则不同
But, my friend, Russian justice plays by different rules.
什么是俄国正义
What is Russian justice?
我怎么描述呢
Oh, how should I describe this?
对了
Yes.
等你下月去伊比沙岛
When you're in Ibiza next month,
你可能会在沙滩醒来
you might wake up on the beach...
发现自己的脚被砍了
without your feet.
好吧
Okay.
我没跟警察说这个  因为
I didn't tell this to the cops because...
我父亲很不喜欢我跟俄国人混
...my father gets furious when I hang with Russians.
我们国家过去交恶  你也知道
Our countries have bad history, you know.
我们处理了点事
Look, I dropped Grigory off at that building
我就把格里戈里送去了那栋楼
after we took care of a little business,
但我没进去
but I never went in.
什么事  毒品吗
What kind of business? Drugs?
不是  他欠我一张
No. He owed me a ticket
去一个俄国领事馆宴会的门票
to a reception at the Russian consulate.
到时会场里到处都会是俄国模特
It will be wall-to-wall Russian models.
是啊  俄国女人美得不像话
Yes. Russian women are devastatingly beautiful.
告诉我  你给了格里戈里什么
Tell me... what did you give Grigory
来交换门票呢
in the return for the ticket?
一本手册
A manual
关于如何入侵切诺基电脑的
on how to hack the computer of a Cherokee automobile.
好奇怪的要求
This is a strange request.
他为什么要那个
What did he want with that?
他没说
He didn't say.
我发誓
I swear.
他要在楼里见谁
Who was he meeting in this building?
我不知道
I have no idea.
好吧
Very well.
祝你愉快
Have a nice day.
那么...
So, uh...
我们没事了吧
We're cool, right?
你怎么让尤尔根开口的
How the hell did you get Jurgen to talk?
瓦西里让他看到了坦诚的好处
Vasily helped him see the value of honesty.
没办法  我这人善于跟人打交道
What can I say? I'm a people's person.
格里戈里为什么要入侵一辆切诺基
Why would Grigory want to hack a Cherokee?
这或许是为什么
Well, this might explain that.
实验室分析出了
The lab deciphered those characters
格里戈里衬衫上墨迹的原字
from the ink stain they found on Grigory's shirt.
是害死格里戈里母亲的那场车祸的
It is a case number from a state trooper incident report
州警报告的案件代号
for the car accident that killed Grigory's mother.
我猜猜  她当时开的是一辆切诺基
Let me guess. She was driving a Cherokee.
是的
Correct.
那么格里戈里是认为她并非死于事故
So Grigory doesn't think her death was an accident.
这可能就是害死他的事
That might be what got him killed.
据州警报告  安雅·米什金
According to the state trooper's report, Anya Mishkin,
被害人的母亲  死于一场单车事故
our victim's mother, died in a single-vehicle crash
就发生在州北冷泉市9号高速附近
on highway 9 upstate near Cold Springs.
她的车撞到树  凌晨1点过后起火了
Her car hit a tree and burned sometime after 1:00 a.m.
火灾足以掩盖
You know, a fire would cover up
软件遭入侵而引起车祸的证据
any evidence of a software hack causing that crash.
是啊  但卡塞尔  从这些文件中完全
Yeah, but, Castle, there's no indication in these files
-看不出那是一桩谋杀  -但格里戈里显然认为
- that it was murder. - But clearly Grigory thought
有人破坏了他妈妈的车  以杀死她
someone sabotaged his mother's car in order to kill her.
而格里戈里对这个猜想的调查
And investigating that theory
害他被破坏者所杀
got Grigory killed by the saboteur.
换我说也不能说得更好了
I couldn't have said it better myself.
据账目显示  四天前
According to the financial records, four days ago,
格里戈里在撞车地点附近一家早餐旅馆住过宿
Grigory stayed in a bed and breakfast near the crash site,
他妈妈死前就住在那里
the same one that his mom was staying in when she died.
联系那家旅馆
Reach out to that bed and breakfast,
看他们是否知道格里戈里去做什么了
see if they know what Grigory was up to.
那我们该去找格里戈里的父亲谈谈了
So, it's left to us to talk to Grigory's father,
看他是否也有同样的怀疑
see if he harbors similar suspicions.
瓦西里  卡塞尔和我已经不再一起合作了
Vasily, uh, Castle and I don't work together any longer.
是啊  这个消息让我难以承受
Yes, news of which is more than I can bear.
我或许把我的失望转达给了你们认识的人
I may have expressed my disappointment to people you know.
失陪
Excuse me.
-贝克特  -比尔  你好啊
- Beckett. - Bill, what's up?
贝克特警监  我需要你跟卡塞尔合作
Captain Beckett, I need you to work with Castle.
局长  不是的
Oh, uh, commissioner, no,
我们已经在尽力协助茨洛夫先生了
we are doing everything we can to assist Mr. Zhirov.
是啊  我见过他了  他挺有个性
Yeah, I've met him. He's, uh, a character.
我很乐意跟他们合作
I would love to work with them.
我很乐意让卡塞尔跟我们合作
I would love to have Castle work with us.
-那好  再见  -谢谢
- All right. Bye. - Thank you.
太棒了
Fantastic.
我们可以中途去吃个披萨
We can stop for pizza.
-好吧  -嗯
- Okay. - Yeah.
嗯  那个俄国孩子上周来住店的
Yeah, that Russian kid stayed here last week.
小可怜问起了他妈妈
Poor guy was asking about his mom.
她很喜欢来我们旅馆住
She loved staying here at my bed and breakfast.
事故真是太遗憾了
What a shame about the accident.
你都记得她什么
What do you remember about her?
人不错  带了个男友在这儿住了几晚
Nice lady. Stayed here a few nights with a boyfriend.
你知道他的名字吗
Did you get his name?
不知道  抱歉
No. Sorry.
你能形容他一下吗
Can you describe him?
不止形容
I can do you one better.
那孩子也问了同样的问题
The kid was asking the same question,
所以我调出了监控  找到了
so I pulled security video and got...
这个
this.
米什金先生  你儿子或
Mr. Mishkin, was there anything in your son
亡妻有任何值得怀疑的行为吗
or late wife's behavior that would merit suspicion?
如果有  我就会跟我们保安人员说了
If there was, I would have told our security agents.
你妻子为什么去州北
What was your wife doing upstate?
她应该是在搞外遇
I believe she was having an affair.
-跟谁  -我不清楚
- Uh, with whom? - I don't know.
我们已经疏远了
We have grown apart,
但我们又都想继续驻在这儿
but we both wanted to serve at this post,
所以我们各过各的
so we led separate lives.
我们得去别处
We have to go someplace.
失陪一下
Excuse us, please.
我需要她的联络人名单
I'll need her contact list,
以及其他能帮我们查清
along with anything else that could help us
她可能出轨对象的信息
identify who she might have been seeing.
当然  我会给你备好的
Yes, of... of course. I'll have it ready for you.
这什么地方
What is this place?
通讯办公室
Communication office.
绝密
Top secret.
只限最高权限
Alpha clearance only.
-酷啊  -是啊
- Cool. - Yes.
但如果他们发现你进来可就糟了
But not so cool if they catch you here.
你会被枪决的
You'll be shot.
不是开玩笑  我们得赶紧
It's no joke. We must hurry.
-好吧  -很可能格里戈里
- Okay. - It is possible that Grigory,
最新美剧下载
www.ZiMuZu.tv
虽说他不在这儿工作
even though he did not work here,
在我们的私人服务器上有电邮账号
kept a dedicated e-mail account on our private server.
这样我们就能进一步
This will tell us a little bit more
了解他对他母亲之死的调查了
about his investigation into his mother's death.
没错  在这儿呢
Yes. And there it is.
有来自艾米丽2929的加急邮件
I see urgent e-mails from emily2929,
求他打给她
Pleading for him to call her.
她很怕  还说他俩都有麻烦了
She's scared, states that they're both in trouble.
最后一封是他死的那天发的
And the last one was sent the day he died.
但艾米丽2929是谁
But who's emily2929?
艾米丽·哈珀  你知道你为什么被找来吗
Emily Hopper, do you know why you're here?
是为格里戈里·米什金的事吗
This is about Grigory Mishkin?
嗯  你跟他是什么关系
Yeah, what was your relationship with him?
你想撒谎
You're about to lie.
别
Don't do it.
对你没好处
It will not be good for you.
我几天前见过他
I saw him a couple of days ago.
我一直喜欢他  我们就约了一炮
I'd always had a thing for him, so we hooked up.
但仅此而已  不管这是为什么事
But that's it. Whatever this is about,
不管他做了什么  都跟我没关系
whatever he did, I-I had nothing to do with it.
你以为这是为什么事呢
And what do you think this is about, exactly?
我不知道
I don't know.
没什么
Nothing.
艾米丽  格里戈里死了
Emily, Grigory is dead.
天呐
Oh, god.
你最后见他时发生了什么事
What happened the last time you saw him?
你为什么给他发邮件要求他见你
Why did you send him e-mails demanding he call you?
我们那啥之后我睡着了
I fell asleep after we...
我醒来时  我以为我看到他在用我的电脑
When I woke up, I-I thought I saw him on my laptop.
他否认了  但他走后
He denied it, but after he left,
我发现他用了我的工作登录读取了一位客户的数据
I realized that he'd used my work login to access a client's data.
你做什么的
And what kind of work do you do?
我是一家数据存储公司的
I work with a data storage company.
我们为公司存储文件
We archive files for businesses
也为一些政府机构存储文件
and some government agencies.
好吧  你得告诉我格里戈里在找的是什么文件
Okay, you need to tell me what files Grigory was looking at.
他看的东西可能害死了他
Whatever he saw might have gotten him killed.
埃斯波
Espo.
过来
Come here.
关门
Close the door.
艾米丽·哈珀的云存储公司为联调局管理老档案
Emily Hopper's cloud storage company archives old FBI files.
那就是格里戈里要的
That's what Grigory was after.
什么联调局档案
What kind of FBI files?
一场1980年代的冷战行动
A 1980s cold war operation
目的是确认并揭露苏联潜伏美国的特工
to identify and flip Soviet sleeper agents in the U.S.
潜伏特工
Sleepers?
那不是传言吗
I thought directorate s was a myth.
不  是真的
No, it was very real.
联调局抓的最大的鱼就是克格勃特工阿纳托利·阿尔卡迪
And the FBI's biggest catch was KGB agent Anatoly Arkady.
87年  他叛逃了
In '87, he defected
以弗兰克·托马斯加入证人保护计划
and went into witness protection as Frank Thomas.
这就是如今的弗兰克  还住在美国呢
And that's Frank present day, still living in the U.S.
这是那家早餐旅馆的那人
This is our guy from the bed and breakfast.
而这个女人  就是格里戈里的妈妈
And the woman in here is Grigory's mother,
安雅·米什金
Anya Mishkin,
也是一位苏联特工
Also a Soviet agent.
她是个间谍
She's a spy.
这事比外遇出问题大多了
This is bigger than an illicit affair gone wrong.
我开始觉得  我们这位友好的俄国人
And I'm beginning to think that our friendly Russian
可能知道一些事却没说
knows more than he's telling.
瓦西里
Vasily.
我能借走卡塞尔和莱恩一下吗
Hey, can I borrow Castle and Ryan for a couple minutes?
是关于莱恩婴儿送礼会的事
It's about Ryan's baby shower.
需要几个美国人策划一场婴儿送礼会啊
How many American men does it take to plan a baby shower?
三个
Um, three.
-是啊  -嗯  走吧
- Yeah. - Yeah. Shall we?
哈维  怎么回事
Hey, Javi, what's going on?
你知道瓦西里是否认得此人吗
You know if Vasily recognized this guy?
-不认识吧  -怎么了
- I don't think so. - Why do you ask?
因为弗兰克真名是阿纳托利·阿尔卡迪
Because Frank's real name is Anatoly Arkady.
他是冷战时期从俄国叛逃的人
He's a defector from Russia from back in the cold war. And...
格里戈里的妈妈安雅是个间谍
Grigory's mom, Anya, is a spy.
-真的  -嗯
- Really? - Yeah.
这也太酷了
That is so cool...
糟糕...显然很糟糕
Bad. It's obviously bad.
他们的关系不是情人吗
Their relationship wasn't romantic?
我们不确定他们是什么关系
We're not sure what their relationship was.
不管怎样  我们现在知道
Either way, we now know
瓦西里的动机不可信
that Vasily's motives cannot be trusted.
一个叛逃者重新出现  一个间谍死亡
A defector resurfaces, a spy dies,
而她儿子大半夜被杀
and her son is killed in the middle of the night.
生活简直比小说还精彩
This novel writes itself.
那接下来会发生什么
Tell us what happens next.
我不知道  所以才精彩
I have no idea. That's what makes it so good.
弗兰克  也就是阿纳托利
Frank, A.K.A. Anatoly,
是搞清凶案真相的关键
is the key to figuring out what's behind these murders,
你们去查他的生活  看能发现什么
so you guys dig into his life and see what you can find.
那我们拿瓦西里怎么办
What do you want us to do about Vasily?
我们得尽量让他远离案子
We got to keep him as far away from this case as possible,
所以我们得启动游览行动
which means we need to launch operation nickel tour.
好吧
Right.
那是什么
What's that?
你得带他去观光
You're gonna take him sightseeing.
看他知道什么
See what he knows.
与此同时  我去找联调局聊聊
In the meantime, I'm gonna talk to the Feds
看他们是否对
and see if they have any intel
阿纳托利再次开始行动知情
on Anatoly returning to active status.
喂
Hello.
我的窗帘需要洗了
I need my curtains cleaned.
瓦西里
Vasily.
宝宝派对的事忙完了
Is the baby party emergency resolved?
是的  是的  还有好消息
Oh, yeah, yeah. And, uh, good news.
小伙子们有好多调查要做
The boys have hours and hours of research to do,
好多电话要打
phone calls for the case.
所以我想  何不借此机会
So I thought why not take this chance
带你在我们称为家的小岛上逛逛
to show you around this little island we call home.
现在难道不是关键时期吗
Is this not a critical juncture?
我可不想开小差
I don't want to be a shirker.
没事  开会儿小差不妨害任何人
Oh, come on. A little shirking never hurt anyone.
我们去有草坪的酒吧吃个午餐
We'll have a late lunch at tavern on the green,
然后做马车在公园转一圈
and, uh, a carriage ride around the park.
这是传统
It's a tradition.
这就是为什么我们用手机嘛
Oh. This is why we have cellphones, huh?
没错  我们走吧
Exactly! Let's go.
我想多听些你的事
So, I want to hear more about you.
外交安全听上去很炫啊
Diplomatic security sounds fascinating.
就好像剧院
Ah. It's like theater.
每个人都扮演一个角色  但其实他们是另一回事
Everyone pretends to be one thing when, really, they're another.
没人关心结果之外的东西
And nobody cares about anything but the results.
老板嘛  对吧
Ah. Bosses, right?
他们知道什么  你向谁汇报
What do they know? Who do you report to?
抱歉  是我妈妈的电话
Sorry, my mamotchka needs attention,
-没问题吧  -听着
- If it's okay? - Oh, listen,
我很了解有个需要关注的老妈
I know a thing or two about having a needy mamotchka.
是理查德·卡塞尔
It's the Richard Castle.
不客气
Do svidaniya.
她听说我遇见你十分激动
She is most excited that I met you.
我可以送本
Oh, well, I'm sure an autographed copy
亲笔签名的新书
of my latest book could be arranged.
太好了
Amazing.
她还想要些纪念品
She also requested a few souvenirs.
-我们能走了  -随你去哪都行
- We can go? - Anywhere you like.
丽塔  谢谢你这么快能见我
Rita, thank you for meeting with me so quickly.
我乐意  虽然我在运营脱衣舞俱乐部
I like it. Although when I ran ops in strip clubs,
我们敞开门做生意
we were open for business.
我有两起谋杀案
Okay, so I've got two murders,
所有线索都指向
and all roads lead towards
一名80年代的俄罗斯叛逃者  阿纳托利·阿尔卡迪
a Russian defector from the '80s, Anatoly Arkady.
没啥印象
Doesn't ring a bell.
联调局把他列入证人保护计划
Okay, well, the FBI put him in wit-pro
化名弗兰克·托马斯
Under the name Frank Thomas,
我想你能否不动声色地打探一下
And I was hoping you could put out a few quiet feelers,
看看他是否在搞新的行动
see if he's working a new operation.
我会处理的
I'll take care of it.
好的
Okay.
你到底做了
You really did it.
你把婚事搞砸了
You blew up your marriage
掉进了洛克塞特的兔子洞里
and went down the LokSat rabbit hole.
什么
What?
不  没有
No-- nothing.
只是说  你有在关注我们
It's just that, um, well, you've been watching us,
你认为我们俩掰了
and you think that we're broken up.
但是你们没有
But you're not.
我爱这个性趣小花招
Oh, I love a little sexual subterfuge.
让一切变得很性感
Oh, it makes things so much hotter.
所以卡塞尔扮成
So, Castle is playing tour guide
一名俄罗斯外交安全人员的导游
to a Russian diplomatic security officer.
他名字叫瓦西里
His name's Vasily --
瓦西里·茨洛夫
Vasily Zhirov?
是的  你认识他
Yeah. Do you know him?
他是俄罗斯外情局的杀手
He's a cleaner with Russian foreign intelligence.
所以外交安全只是个幌子
So diplomatic security's just a cover?
-是的  -那他真正的使命是
- Yeah. - Then what's his real mission?
谁知道呢
Who knows?
但你丈夫要是挡了瓦西里的路
But if your husband gets in Vasily's way,
他可就是附带的牺牲品了
He's gonna be collateral damage.
除非你老妈
Um, unless your mamotchka
喜欢老鼠屎和污染的针头
is a fan of rat droppings and dirty needles,
这里实在没有啥纪念品
there's really not much around here by the way of souvenirs.
她的品味很不寻常
Her tastes can be unusual.
其实我之前说谎了
Actually, I lied about earlier.
为什么  你为什么这么干
Why -- why did you do that?
别担心
Don't worry.
你很快就会知道
You'll soon find out.
瓦西里
Vasily.
嘿
Hey, hey, hey --
你在搞什么
What are you doing?
瓦西里  放开我
Vasily, get off me.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我们的公园马车之旅得等等了
Our carriage ride around the park will have to wait.
你是谁
Who are you?
显然你不是什么
Obviously you're not some
无忧无虑的外交安全人员
Happy-go-lucky diplomatic security agent.
你记得阿诺德·施瓦辛格吗
You remember Arnold Schwarzenegger
在《红色警探》电影里
In the movie "Red heat," Yes?
和我比起来  他那角色就是个柔弱非暴力的小孩子
Compared to me, his character is like weak, non-violent child.
你好  暖男
Hello, sunshine.
快点  过来
Come on. Come on.
俄罗斯情报截获有关
Russian intelligence picked up chatter about an attack
俄罗斯公民在美国遇袭的对话
on Russian citizens in the united states.
如果的确发生  俄罗斯人死在美国土地上
If that happens, dead Russians on American soil,
会对两国都很不利
it will be very bad for both our countries.
那我们把此事转交国土安全局
So we take that to homeland security.
不行
I cannot.
传言袭击者是俄罗斯人
It is believed the attackers are Russian.
你现在明白了吗
Do you understand now?
我认为安雅·米什金和这个叛徒
I believe anya mishkin and this traitor
合谋了此事
are part of the conspiracy.
可怜的格里戈里被谋杀了
Poor Grigory got murdered
因为他偶然卷进来
Because he stumbled into it.
我得撬开他的嘴
I must break him.
我什么都不会告诉你  同志
I'm not telling you squat, comrade.
你听到了吗  里克
Do you hear that, Rick?
你别想让我开口
You couldn't get me to talk --
虽然他几十年都像美国人一样生活
Even though he lived as an American all these decades,
他依旧有颗俄国心
still he's Russian in his heart.
但我会让他软下来
But I will soften him up.
像炎热夏日的冰淇淋一样
Like ice cream on a hot summer day.
哇哦  我不能让你这么干
Whoa, whoa, whoa! I can't let you do that.
里克  你是个好人
Rick, you're a nice guy.
我喜欢你
I like you.
所以
So, please...
别逼我也折磨你
Don't make me hurt you, too.
拜托了
Please.
拜托告诉我  你能联系上瓦西里和卡塞尔
Please tell me you have a line on Vasily and Castle.
-还没  -你有定位到卡塞尔的手机吗
- Nothing yet. - Did you ping Castle's phone?
手机关机了
It's been deactivated.
痛苦是我们唯一的通途
Pain is the only way we get through.
-还有其他办法  -不  没有了
- There's another way. - No, there is not!
总是有其他办法的
There is always another way.
我也想有更多时间跟你逗乐
Look, I wish I had more time to humor you --
60秒  只要给我60秒
60 seconds. Just give me 60 seconds.
-求你了  -60秒
- Please. - 60 seconds?
好吧  看看你有什么本事
Fine. Show me what you got.
开始
Uh, go.
显然如果你直接告诉他需要的信息
All right, obviously this would go a lot easier
就容易多了
if you would just tell him what he needs to know.
好吧  他需要知道的就是
Okay. What he needs to know is
-你们俩都去死吧  -开玩笑吧
- that you can both go screw yourselves! - Really?!
里克  我不想无礼  但目前为止我可不满意
Rick, I hate to be rude, but so far I'm not impressed.
-还有55秒  -好的好的
- 55 seconds! - Okay, okay, okay.
如果  如果弗兰克是这场阴谋的中心人物
If -- if Frank is at the center of this conspiracy,
他身上就可能有些线索
then he may have some clues on him
能帮我们找到袭击发生的地点
as to where the attack is going to take place.
-还有42秒  -收据
- 42 seconds. - Receipt.
这张收据是买的
There's a receipt for a...
压膜工具
Lamination kit.
这到底说明什么
Which means what, exactly?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
太棒了  还有42秒
Very good. 42 seconds.
41秒
41.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
他的地图记录显示搜索过卖制服的商店
All right, his map history has a search for uniform stores.
通话记录
Okay. Call history.
上周给同一个号码打过三个电话
Called the same number three times the last week.
-还剩29秒  -谢谢
- 29 seconds. - Thank you.
太有意思了  不是吗
This is fun, no?
是餐饮服务商
It's a caterer.
为什么打给餐饮公司  我遗漏了什么信息
Why a catering company? What am I missing?
又花了这么长时间  只剩24秒
More time. Only 24 seconds left.
拜托  没开玩笑吧
Come on. Seriously?
好吧
All right, okay.
压膜工具是
Lamination kit is --
你在做假证件
It's, uh, you're making fake I.D.s
做假证好让人混进餐饮公司
Making fake i.d.s to get someone into a catering company.
为什么呢
Why?
为了混进一场重大活动
To slip into an event.
什么活动呢
But what event?
你是想
You're...
在俄罗斯领事馆举办的宴会
The party at the Russian consulate.
你做假证是为了让人穿成服务员的样子
You're making a fake I.D. to sneak someone into a party
混进在俄罗斯领事馆举办的宴会
at the russian consulate dressed as catering staff.
对不对
Right?!
天才
Brilliant!
还剩了点时间呢
And with time to spare!
实际上没剩  宴会马上开始了
Actually, no. The party's about to begin.
我们得抓紧了
We must hurry.
我要打给贝克特  让她安排警员把弗兰克接走
I'm gonna call Beckett, have unis pick Frank up.
让他们在领事馆和我们见面
Have them meet us at the consulate.
再见  弗兰克
Bye, Frank.
各位
Guys.
他们不让我们进去
They're denying us entry.
因为这里算是俄罗斯领土
Because this is considered Russian soil,
我们不能强行闯进去
We can't force our way in.
为什么总领事还没取消宴会
Why hasn't the consul general canceled the party yet?
怎么说呢  对生意不利
How do you say? This is not good for business.
如果奥伯林没有确凿证据就取消宴会
If Oborin cancels without credible proof,
在敌人眼中就太软弱了
he looks weak in the eyes of his adversaries.
政治比死亡威胁还重要
Politics wins over death threats?
在俄罗斯  宁可丢性命也不能丢面子
In Russia, it's better to be killed than lose face.
你现在就得把我们弄进去
You need to get us in. Now.
-只有受邀才能进去  -那就邀请我们
- It's invite only. - So invite us.
我们算你的同伴
We'll be your plus four.
计划是什么  我们连目标是谁都不知道
So what's the plan? We don't even know who the target is.
找找有没有人格格不入或者举止怪异
Look for anyone out of place or acting unusual.
我们知道袭击者穿着
Well, we know their attacker is dressed
和服务员一样  是吧
as one of the catering staff, right?
不一定
Well, not necessarily.
他们可能穿着服务员的衣服进的大门
They may have used the catering outfit to gain entry,
但是现在到了里面
But now that they're inside,
混进来的那位可能会设法融入环境
our infiltrator may try to blend in.
是的  很有道理
Yes, yes, very true.
但是各位  重点是我给你们做担保了
But, guys, most important -- I vouched for you.
我要维护我的江湖名声
I have street cred to protect.
所以  拜托了
So, please...
保持冷静好吗
Stay cool, yeah?
-这里没香槟  -我去给你们拿点
- No champagne. - I'll go get you some, yeah?
-好的  -三杯
- Yeah. - Three.
有狙击手
Sniper!
你没事吧
Are you okay?
好像是吧
I -- I think so.
我觉得没事
I think so.
快叫救护车
Somebody call an ambulance!
谢尔盖  谢尔盖
Sergei! Sergei!
子弹彻底从他身上穿透了
Bullet went through and through.
谢尔盖在做手术
Sergei's in surgery right now.
应该可以痊愈
He's expected to make a full recovery.
-有枪手的消息吗  -我们在领事馆对面
- Anything on the shooter? - Yeah, we found a sniper's nest
那条街上一栋楼里发现了狙击手的掩体
In the building across the street from the consulate.
找到监控录像了吗
Any luck with security video?
被破坏了  但是我们找到一套清洁工服
Disabled, but we found a janitor's uniform
还有狙击手的武器
and the sniper's weapon.
是俄制德拉贡诺夫狙击步枪
It's a Russian-made Dragunov.
鉴证组找到指纹或者DNA了吗
Did CSU pull prints or DNA?
他们在努力  但我怀疑他们什么都找不到
They're trying, but I doubt they're gonna find anything.
干这票的人是专业的
Whoever pulled this off is a pro.
枪手因格里戈里发现
Which means I.D.ing our shooter
行刺企图将其杀害
who most likely killed Grigory
现在确认这枪手身份
when he found out about this whole assassination plot
几乎是不可能完成的任务
is gonna be damn near impossible.
还有更糟的
And it only gets worse.
俄罗斯人宣称是我们转移了
The Russians are claiming that we created a distraction
他们安保团队的注意力
for their security team, which allowed for
才让刺杀总领事的行动有机可乘
the assassination attempt on their consul general.
等等  你救了总领事的命
Well, hold up. You saved the consul's ass,
他们就是这样感谢我们的
And this is the thanks we get?
更有甚者  他们拒绝继续和我们合作
Plus they're refusing any further cooperation with us
调查格里戈里的谋杀案
on Grigory's murder investigation.
-他们为什么要这样做  -我不
- Why would they do that? - I don't --
因为我们害怕了
Because we are scared.
我们的麻烦怪罪美国更简单
It is easier to blame America for our troubles,
但真相是我们在内斗
when the truth is we're fighting ourselves.
这算是道歉吗
That supposed to be an apology?
听着不像啊
It didn't sound like one.
刺杀奥伯林未遂事件
The attempt on Oborin's life
震惊了整个俄罗斯外交圈
has shaken everyone in the Russian diplomatic community.
没人知道该信任谁
No one knows who to trust.
我失去了奥伯林对我仅有的些许信任
And what little faith Oborin has in me he has now lost.
所以现在你孤立无援
So now that you're all out of friends,
就来找我们帮忙了
You've come to us for help.
拜托了  警监
Please, Captain.
你对我说过你只想
You told me all you wanted
把幕后混蛋凶手捉拿归案
is to get the son of a bitch behind this.
帮我格里戈里  安雅和谢尔盖伸张正义吧
Help me get justice for Grigory, Anya, and Sergei.
好吧
Fine.
但是我必须让另一个人参与进来
But I have to bring someone else in.
没搞错吧
Get out of town.
好久不见
Long time, no see.
上次见面还是在那个地方的那件事
Since that thing at the place.
你是说在那个地方那个人的事
You mean the place with the guy?
不  不是那个人
Nyet. Not that guy.
另外一个人
The other guy.
头超大的那个人
The guy with the big, massive head.
噢  那家伙  我记得他
Oh! That guy! I remember.
他的下场可不怎么样
Things didn't end well for him.
估计你也不会有什么好下场
They may not end well for you, either.
还用得着你提醒么
Like I don't know that.
好吧  此时此刻
So, right here, right now,
把你的底牌亮出来吧
lay all your cards on the table.
俄罗斯驻纽约的领事馆里有个泄密者
The Russian consulate in New York has a leak.
-情况有多糟  -很糟糕
- How bad? - Critical.
敏感情报在拍卖会上被匿名售卖
Sensitive intelligence is being sold anonymously at auction.
两个月前  我动用了安雅·米什金
Two months ago, I activated Anya Mishkin
去找出那个叛徒
to identify the traitor.
我猜那个叛徒抢先一步搞定了她
I'm guessing the traitor got to her first.
安雅最后一次报告
Anya's last communique
说她就快揭开那个人的真面目了
said she was close to unmasking him.
但之后她就死于一场车祸
But then she was killed in a car crash.
你们的叛徒把她灭口了
Your traitor silenced her.
我们需要人名
We need names.
你们的怀疑名单上都有谁
Who's on your list?
分享是相互的
There's sharing,
你分享给我  我分享给你
and then there's sharing.
她是国务院的人
So, she's from the State Department?
事实上  那只是个假身份
Actually, that's just a cover.
为了隐藏什么  她的真实身份是谁
Cover for what? Who is she?
丽塔有很多身份
Rita is many things,
其中有一重身份是你的继母
One of which is your stepmother.
她一直在帮我追查洛克塞特
She's been helping me take down LokSat.
我  我本想早点告诉你  但是
I -- I wanted to tell you sooner, but --
我猜猜
Let me guess.
你不能告诉我  因为你想保护我
You couldn't because you needed to protect me.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
老是这一套说辞  贝克特
This is getting really old, Beckett.
我知道  相信我  的确是
I know. Believe me, it is
老一套
Old.
真的非常老套
It's very old.
谢谢
Thank you.
卡塞尔  你说的完全对
Castle, you're absolutely right.
就是嘛  等等  你说什么
Exactly. Wait. What --
什么对了
Right about --
我说什么说对了
What was I right about?
关于那把德拉贡诺夫狙击步枪的报告
The report on the dragunov sniper rifle
说它的枪管缠距是320毫米
said that the barrel twist rate was 320 millimeters.
但是新型号的缠距是240毫米  对吗
But the newer version is 240, right?
没错  是90年代改进的
Yes, it was changed in the '90s.
有威力大得多  精准度更好的新型枪
So then why would our sniper use an older model
这个狙击手为什么要用旧款
when the newer one is so much more powerful and accurate?
那一定是杀手唯一能拿到的武器
It - it must have been the only thing the assassin had access to.
但到底是谁会随手留下一把1980年代的
Only who the hell leaves around a russian sniper rifle
俄国狙击步枪呢
from the 1980s lying around?
闪电
Molniya.
Lightning?
这是一个克格勃代号  指在北约国家
It's an old KGB code name for weapon caches
秘密存放的武器库
planted in NATO countries
它们可以支持在外行动的特工
to support the agents in the field.
前苏联解体之后
After the dissolution of the Soviet Union,
它们很多都被废弃了
many were abandoned.
但某些参与过行动的人会知道它们在哪
But someone in the field would know where they were.
比如弗兰克  但他已经请了律师
Like frank. Except he's all lawyered up.
是的  但是  我也知道那些武器藏在哪
Yes, but I, too, know where these old caches are.
我们搜查那些武器库  就能找到凶手
We search those caches, we could find our killer.
你让我想起杰克逊
You remind me of Jackson.
我觉得这话不大可信
I find that very hard to believe.
你有和他一样的眼睛和淘气的笑容
You have his eyes and that mischievous grin.
就是这个笑容
There it is.
他还好吗
How is he?
他活着
Alive.
干我们这行  活着就是你所希望的一切
In our business, that's all you can hope for.
他有没有
Does he ever, um...
提到过我
mention me?
没有
No.
你就不能说个谎哄我吗
You couldn't have lied?
那并不代表他不惦念你
Doesn't mean he's not thinking of you.
不得不远离你  这是他的应对方式
Just how he deals with having to have to stay away.
他这么做是为了你的安全
He does it for your own safety.
我真不喜欢人们为了我的安全把我推开
I am so sick of people pushing me away for my safety.
我猜尤其是贝克特  对吗
Specifically beckett, I'm assuming?
还是有点沮丧  是吧
Still a wee bit upset, huh?
怒气时不时会燃起来  的确是
The anger flares up from time to time, yes.
她这么做是出于爱
She did it out of love.
我明白
Oh, I know.
明白
I know.
到头来
At the end of the day,
她让一切都值得了
She's worth it.
我很高兴见到了你  理查德
I'm glad I met you, richard.
我也很高兴见到你
I'm glad I met you, too.
但你从没见过我  记住
But you didn't. Remember that.
当然  你的秘密很安全
No, your secret is safe.
我还能再见到你或者我爸么
Am I going to see you or my dad again?
他非常非常为你感到骄傲
He's so very proud of you.
伙计们  你们肯定想看看这个
Hey, guys. You're gonna want to see this.
我一直在看城里所有冷战时期
I've been scrubbing traffic cam footage
旧武器库周边的交通监控
at the addresses of all the old cold war caches in the city.
发现了什么
What did you find?
你们得看了才会相信
Well, you have to see it to believe it.
这是昨天的录像
This is from yesterday.
-那是谁  -我来展示给你
- who's that? - I'll show you.
等着看吧
Wait for it.
还记得我们的冷战间谍阿纳托利和安雅吗
Remember our cold war spies Anatoly and Anya?
这是她现在的样子
This is her now.
这是安雅·米什金
This is Anya Mishkin.
格里戈里的母亲
Grigory's mother.
但她不是死于一场车祸吗
But she died in the car crash.
没有  她活得好好的
Nope. She's alive and well.
一定是她从武器库里拿了狙击枪
She must have taken the dragunov from the gun cache.
现在我们知道杀手是谁了
Now we know who our assassin is.
你指望我相信
Do you expect me to believe
你对于安雅还活着毫不知情
that you had no idea Anya was still alive?
我发誓  我所知道的是
I swear it. For all I know,
一直以来安雅就是俄领事馆里的泄密者
Anya's the leak in the russian consulate all along!
她伪装了自己的死亡就是为了迷惑你
And she faked her death just to throw you off?
我不知道
I don't know.
警监  对安雅
Captain, that bolo
上的那辆偷来的车发的通缉有回应了
that I put on the stolen car that anya got into paid off.
警员在长岛高速公路把她拦下了
Unis pulled her over on the L.I.E.
他们拘押她了吗
Do they have her in custody?
立刻把她带来
Bringing her in right now.
我来审讯她
I'll question her.
你们到底在玩什么把戏  安雅
So, what was the endgame, anya?
卖情报的钱
Money for selling secrets
存在一个开曼群岛的账户里好让
in a cayman account so that you and frank
你和弗兰克可以享受沙滩
could sit on a beach?
你根本不知道自己在说什么
You have no idea what you are talking about.
但是这场梦幻隐居计划的代价太高了
But the price for this fantasy getaway was steep --
它让你儿子送了命
Your son's life.
所以是谁杀了他  是弗兰克吗
So who killed him? Was it frank?
或者是你亲自动的手
Or did you do it yourself?
我所做的一切都是为了救他
Everything I've done was in order to save him.
格里戈里发现了真相
Grigory found out the truth, didn't he?
他威胁说要揭发你
And he threatened to expose you.
所以你杀了他
That's why you killed him.
我想不通的是  你为什么会
The thing I don't understand is, why did you stick around
为了杀领事馆的人而留下来
for the assassination attempt at the consulate?
我只想复仇
All I had left was vengeance.
奥伯林对你做了什么
What did Oborin do to you?
我瞄准的不是奥伯林
I wasn't aiming for Oborin.
谢尔盖
Sergei.
你瞄准的是你丈夫
You were aiming for your husband?
要是你没插手
And if you hadn't interfered,
他现在已经死了  他就应该死
he would be dead now, as he should be.
我得说  里克
I must say, Rick,
你小说里的贝克特没有真人厉害啊
your novels don't do Beckett justice.
她这才刚开始
She's just getting started.
我不像你想的那样是个恶魔
I am not the devil you think I am.
我不是叛徒
I am not a traitor.
-但你丈夫是叛徒  -对
- But your husband is? - Yes.
谢尔盖才是那个把我们的商业秘密
Sergei is the one who's been selling our trade secrets
告诉竞争对手的人  我有证据
to economic competitors -- I have proof.
那你为什么不告诉瓦西里  是因为爱吗
And why didn't you tell Vasily? Was it love?
不是爱
Not love.
我沉默是因为我丈夫后台很硬
I held my tongue because my husband is very well connected.
比瓦西里的后台硬得多
Much more so than Vasily.
很不幸  里克  这些都是真的
Sadly, Rick, this is all true.
要是我告发谢尔盖
If I had turned Sergei in,
他会用政治手段除掉我
he would have used his political muscle to bury me.
我会被审判  而不是他
I would have been the one on trial, not him.
在俄国法律一无是处
Laws mean nothing in Russia.
政治权力说了算
All that matters is power.
你为了自我保护  假装死亡
So you faked your death to protect yourself.
但格里戈里起了疑心
But Grigory became suspicious.
他发现了谢尔盖在干什么
He got on to the truth of what Sergei was doing.
安雅  你是说谢尔盖杀了格里戈里吗
Anya, are you saying that Sergei killed Grigory?
他们没有血缘关系
They're not blood.
格里戈里的生父在他出生前就去世了
Grigory's biological father died before his birth.
谢尔盖和格里戈里从来都不亲近
Sergei never truly bonded with Grigory.
我跟着格里戈里去了那栋公寓楼
I followed Grigory to that apartment building,
但已经太迟了
but I was too late.
我看着谢尔盖逃跑  然后...
I saw Sergei running away, and then...
我发现了我可怜的孩子
I found my poor boy.
那你为什么用狙击枪复仇呢
And why did you try to get revenge with a sniper rifle?
因为谋杀发生后  谢尔盖没离开过领事馆
Because Sergei never left the consulate after the murder.
那晚是最好的机会  也是最后的机会
That night was my best chance, my last chance!
他马上就要回俄国了  我就束手无策了
Soon he will go back to Russia and be out of my reach.
我向你保证  我会尽我所能
I promise you I will do everything in my power
确保他被绳之以法
to make sure that he is brought to justice.
我丈夫有完全外交豁免权
My husband has full diplomatic immunity.
你无能为力  我也是
You are powerless, just like I am.
别那么肯定
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
你没资格进来  警监
You have no business here, captain.
奥伯林先生  你知道
Mr. Oborin, are you aware
谢尔盖一直在出售俄国商业机密吗
that Sergei has been selling Russian trade secrets?
警监  这是俄国事务
Captain, this is a Russian matter.
但他杀了格里戈里
But he killed Grigory just --
这也是俄国事务
And it is a Russian matter.
失陪了  我得赶飞机
If you'll excuse me, I have a plane to catch.
莫斯科召我回去
I've been recalled to Moscow,
我要交一点罚款  开始退休生活
where I shall pay a small fine and begin my retirement.
一笔罚款  这就是惩罚
A fine? That's his punishment?
你能帮我个忙吗
Could you do me a favor?
你能否告诉我妻子  我说
Could you please tell my wife I said...
什么意思
What does that mean?
"毛贼被绞死
"Small thieves get hanged.
大盗仍逍遥"
Great ones go free."
是俄国谚语
It's an old Russian proverb.
奥伯林先生  求您了
Mr. Oborin, please.
撤销谢尔盖的豁免权
Revoke Sergei's immunity.
让他因为谋杀格里戈里受到审判
Have him stand trial for Grigory's murder.
那会树立起非常危险的范例
It would set a very dangerous example.
你看  警监  俄国的司法
You see, captain, uh, Russian justice
非常非常...复杂
is very, very... complicated.
有人想跟你们道别
Oh, here's somebody who would like to say goodbye.
你们俩看起来闷闷不乐的
You two look so unhappy.
真让我伤心
This breaks my heart.
你也要走吗  跟谢尔盖坐同一班飞机
You're, uh, leaving town? Same plane as Sergei?
对  九个小时才能到莫斯科
Yes. Nine hours to Moscow.
有很长时间写
But plenty of time to work on
《火与冰》了  是吧
our "Heat and Ice" collaboration, yes?
其实...
In fact...
我对结尾有个想法
I have an idea for the ending.
-瓦西里  我不知道  -你这么写
- Vasily, I don't know if -- - It goes like this.
妮奇·希特和詹姆森·洛克
Nikki Heat and Jameson Rook
以为邪恶的俄国人逃脱了
think the evil Russian has gotten away.
他们不知道  弗拉基米尔·艾斯开始制定计划
What they don't know is Vladimir Ice has set in motion a plan
把凶手送到俄国偏远的奥伊米亚康
to send the murderer to live out the rest of his miserable life
让他痛苦地度过余生
at a lonely Russian outpost, Oymyakon.
我听说过那个镇
I've heard of that town.
是地球上最冷的地方
That's the coldest place on earth.
在埋葬去世的人之前
It takes four days to warm the ground with bonfire
要花四天时间用篝火化开地面
before they can bury their dead.
谢尔盖要去那儿吗
Is that where Sergei is headed?
在俄国  有比监狱糟糕得多的地方
In Russia, there are far worse places than prison.
我说过  俄国的司法非常复杂
Like I said, Russian justice is very complicated.
来吧
Come here.
够壮实的
Strong.
挺有趣吧
This was fun, no?
-对  -我们改日再做
- Yeah. - We do it again sometime.
提前打电话
Call first.
再见
Do svidaniya.
You, too.
凯特
Kate.
不  来吧
Oh, no. Come on.
谢谢
Thank you.
行了
All right.
对  对
Yes, yes.
跟我希望的结局不完全相同
Not exactly the ending that I was hoping for,
但我觉得也只能如此
but I guess it'll have to do.
贝克特  我们已经在六个国家亲吻过了
You know, Beckett, we've kissed in six different countries.
-是吗  你一直在数吗  -你没数吗
- Really? You're keeping count? - You're not?
无论如何  我们没在俄国吻过
Anyway, one country we haven't kissed in is Russia.
严格来说  现在我们就站在俄国领土上
And technically, right now, we are on Russian soil.
还有一件事
You know, there is one other thing
我们也在六个国家做过
that we've done in six different countries.
过来  宝贝
Idi syuda kroshka.
什么意思
What does that mean?
跟我来  你就知道了
Means follow me and find out.
找个俄语翻译软件
Find a Russian translation app.